U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records 5061
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records
1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5061
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcript of proceedings and exhibits of the Emergency Board No. 146, 1962. Trans World Airlines vs. the Flight Engineers' International Association, TWA Chapter, 1951-1962.
3115432
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 31, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The agreement between the parties -was scheduled to expire on January 1, 1961. Both the Company and the Association filed the required notices of intention to change the agreement in October 1960. Negotiations were begun in November and continued to the end of December when the parties requested the services of the National Mediation Board.
Numerous mediation sessions were held during the next four months, but no agreement was reached, so the National Mediation Board suggested arbitration as required by the Railway Labor Act. This was accepted by the Company and rejected by the Association, On September 15, 1961 the Mediation Board closed its file.
negotiations were resumed and continued to March 2, 1962 but no final agreement could be reached. On March 18, the Association notified the Company of its intention to strike on March 21.
There were more than one hundred separate proposals for revisions in the contract affecting recognition, scope, wages, hours, flight-time pay and credits, training, seniority, adjustment of grievances, vacations, sick leave, insurance benefits and many others, but the issue of crew complement was the central problem in this as in other disputes.
On March 20, 1962, by Executive Order 11011, the President created an Emergency Board consisting of James 0. Hill, Thomas C. Begley and Arthur W. Sempliner. Hearings were held from April 3 to April 18, 1962, and a report and recommendations issued on May 1, 1962.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5006: U.S. Emergency Board No. 174 Records 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5030: U.S. Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material 5036: U.S. Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports 5037: U.S. Emergency Board No. 81 Records 5038: U.S. Emergency Board No. 94 Records 5039: U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records 5040: U.S. Emergency Board No. 106 Records 5042: U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records 5043: U.S. Emergency Board No. 114 Records 5044: U.S. Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits 5045: U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records 5046: U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records 5047: U.S. Emergency Board No. 120 Records 5048: U.S. Emergency Board No. 121 Records 5050: U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records 5051: U.S. Emergency Board No. 125 Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5053: U.S. Emergency Board No. 130 Records 5054: U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5055: U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5056: U.S. Emergency Board No. 135 Records 5057: U.S. Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5058: U.S. Emergency Board No. 138 Records 5059: U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records 5060: U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records 5062: U.S. Emergency Board No. 154 Records 5064: U.S. Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5075: U.S. Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5934: Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Collective bargaining -- Aeronautics -- United States -- Sources; Airlines -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- Sources; United States. Emergency Board No. 146; Flight Engineers' International Association--Sources.; Trans World Airlines--Sources.
3115432
- Transcript. 10 Volumes. 1739 pages. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Carriers' Exhibit 1. Chronology of Trans World Airlines-Flight Engineers' International Association Basic Agreement Negotiations. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Carriers' Exhibit 2. Trans World Airlines and Flight Engineers' International Association opening proposals compared to July 29, 1958 Agreement. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Carriers' Exhibit 3. Trans World Airlines Proposals to Flight Engineers' International Association., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  December 1961.
- Carriers' Exhibit 4. Open items, Trans World Airlines-Flight Engineers' International Association Agreement, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  March 23, 1962.
- Carriers' Exhibit 5. Average Trans World Airline Flight Engineer., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Carriers' Exhibit 6. Excerpt "The Airline Financial Posture." (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Carriers' Exhibit 7. Table - Profit Margins, selected industries (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Carriers' Exhibit 8. Index, Price Stability, Fares and Prices., 1950-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Carriers' Exhibit 9. Growth in Airline Traffic., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Carriers' Exhibit 10. Trends in Passenger Mile Yield., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Carriers' Exhibit 11. Trends in Revenue per Passenger Mile. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Carriers' Exhibit 12. Coach-Economy Per Cent of Total Traffic. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Carriers' Exhibit 13. United States Flag Carriers share of trans-Atlantic market., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Carriers' Exhibit 14. United States Flag Carriers share of trans-Atlantic seating capacity., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Carriers' Exhibit 15. Domestic Trunk line Earnings., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Carriers' Exhibit 16. International Operations of Domestic Trunk lines and Pan American System Earnings., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Carriers' Exhibit 17. Trans World Airlines World Routes. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Carriers' Exhibit 18. Trans World Airlines Passenger Miles. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Carriers' Exhibit 19. Distribution of Operating Revenue Dollar. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Carriers' Exhibit 20. Trans World Airlines Earnings., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Carriers' Exhibit 21. Trans World Airlines Net Profit Margin. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Carriers' Exhibit 22. Trans World Airlines Financial Report., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  February 1962.
- Carriers' Exhibit 23. Trans World Airlines Aircraft introduction dates and cost. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Carriers' Exhibit 24. Productivity and Capital Investment. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Carriers' Exhibit 25. Diagram of Jet Airplane Cockpit - List of carriers with 4-man and 3-man crews. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Carriers' Exhibit 26. First Report of Feinsinger Commission., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  May 24, 1961.
- Carriers' Exhibit 27. No information available. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Carriers' Exhibit 28. Report of "Dash Board," Pan American and Flight Engineers International Association., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  June 20, 1961.
- Carriers' Exhibit 29. Excerpt from Dash Board Report. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Carriers' Exhibit 30. Second Report of Feinsinger Commission., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  October 17, 1961.
- Carriers' Exhibit 31. Report of "Fisher Board," Trans World Airlines and Air Line Pilots Association., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  December 15, 1961.
- Carriers' Exhibit 32. CAB Regulations Part 40, "Pilot in Command." (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Carriers' Exhibit 33. Company proposal on crew complement., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  January 1962.
- Carriers' Exhibit 34. Flight Engineers International Association Supplemental Statement on Feinsinger Report., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  February 23, 1962.
- Carriers' Exhibit 35. Anticipated Reduction Group A Flight Engineers. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Carriers' Exhibit 36. Added costs of application of Commission recommendations. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Carriers' Exhibit 37. Trans World Airlines Flight Engineer wage increase., 1950-1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Carriers' Exhibit 38. Annual wages private industries, Increases., 1949-1960 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Carriers' Exhibit 39. Changes in manufacturing wage rates., 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  January 1960-June 1961.
- Carriers' Exhibit 40. Average Annual Salary, Flight Engineers, Big 4 systems (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Carriers' Exhibit 41. Trans World Airlines Flight Engineers wages versus price index and revenue. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Carriers' Exhibit 42. Trans World Airlines Flight Engineer wages compared with other transportation. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Carriers' Exhibit 43. Trans World Airlines Jet Flight Engineers, wages compared to other jobs. (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Carriers' Exhibit 44. Trans World Airlines Flight Engineers, percent of payroll and of employees. (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Carriers' Exhibit 45. Annual salaries, maintenance personnel. (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Carriers' Exhibit 46. Standard job description: Foreman, Maintenance. (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Carriers' Exhibit 47. Standard job description: Foreman-in-charge, Maintenance. (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Carriers' Exhibit 48. Operational Duty Pay. (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Carriers' Exhibit 49. Pegged Speed. (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Carriers' Exhibit 50. Trans World Airlines Jet Flight Engineers Monthly Pay. (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Carriers' Exhibit 51. Trans World Airlines Flight Engineers 1961 Annual Earnings: 50 most senior and 50 least senior. (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Carriers' Exhibit 52. Jet Flight Engineers non-productive credits for each dollar flight pay. (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Carriers' Exhibit 53. Earnings under Agreement as compared to Company proposal of December 12, 1961 at 80 hours. (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Carriers' Exhibit 54. Flight Engineers domestic earnings by equipment flown (5 airlines) at 85 hours. (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Carriers' Exhibit 55. International Flight Engineers earnings by equipment flown (3 airlines) at 80 hours. (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Carriers' Exhibit 56. Union Counter Proposal on Wages., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  February 22, 1962.
- Carriers' Exhibit 57. Comparison pay yields, Trans World Airlines-Flight Engineers International Association proposals. (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Carriers' Exhibit 58. Comparison pay yields, Flight Engineers International Association proposed yields at 70 hours versus current at 80 hours. (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Carriers' Exhibit 59. Flight Engineers International Association proposal at 70 versus 5 airlines. (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Carriers' Exhibit 60. Comparison of pay yields (international) 70 and 75 hours versus current 80 and 85. (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Carrier's Exhibit 61. Comparison Pay Yields International, Flight Engineers International Association 70 and 75 hours, 3 airlines. (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Carrier's Exhibit 62. Booklet: "Management for Service," ATTA (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Carrier's Exhibit 63. Pay hours versus actual flight hours. (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Carrier's Exhibit 64. Hours on Duty - Domestic (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Carrier's Exhibit 65. Hours away from home - domestic (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Carrier's Exhibit 66. Hours at home - domestic (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Carrier's Exhibit 67. Calendar days at home - domestic (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Carrier's Exhibit 68. Utilization - monthly hours - domestic (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Carrier's Exhibit 69. Hours on duty - international (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Carrier's Exhibit 70. Hours away from home - international (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Carrier's Exhibit 71. Hours at home - international (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Carrier's Exhibit 72. Calendar days at home - international (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Carrier's Exhibit 73. Utilization - monthly hours - international (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Carrier's Exhibit 74. Flight Engineers Proposal - Hours on Duty - Domestic (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Carrier's Exhibit 75. Flight Engineers Proposal - Hours away from home - Domestic (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Carrier's Exhibit 76. Flight Engineers Proposal - Hours at Home - Domestic (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Carrier's Exhibit 77. Flight Engineers Proposal - Calendar days at home - Domestic (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Carrier's Exhibit 78. Flight Engineers Proposal - Hours on Duty - International (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Carrier's Exhibit 79. Flight Engineers Proposal - Hours away from home - International (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Carrier's Exhibit 80. Flight Engineers Proposal - Hours at home - International (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Carrier's Exhibit 81. Flight Engineers Proposal - Calendar days at home - International (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Carrier's Exhibit 82. Company Proposals - Flight Scheduling, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  December 12, 1961
- Carrier's Exhibit 83. Trans World Airlines versus National Airlines - Pay and Conditions. (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Carrier's Exhibit 84. Flight Engineers International Association versus National Airlines - Selected Provisions (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Carrier's Exhibit 85. Kennedy on shorter workweek. (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Carrier's Exhibit 86. Clement wire regarding flight engineer utilization., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  April 5, 1962
- Carrier's Exhibit 87. Credit at 1 to 2 duty. (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Carrier's Exhibit 88. Credit at 1 to 4. (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Carrier's Exhibit 89. Credit at 1 to 2, 1 to 4. (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Carrier's Exhibit 90. Credit - actual or scheduled, how operational time determined. (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Carrier's Exhibit 91. Flight Assignments., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  March 1, 1962.
- Carrier's Exhibit 92. International Flight Assignments - Turbine. (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Carrier's Exhibit 93. International Flight Assignments - Piston. (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Carrier's Exhibit 94. Pay hours., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Carrier's Exhibit 95. Working Conditions, Summer 1961 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- Carrier's Exhibit 96. Average Utilization of Flight Engineers. (Box 1, Folder 97)
- Carrier's Exhibit 97. Trans World Airlines Proposal "Trip Hours" - Definition. (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Carrier's Exhibit 98. Trans World Airlines Proposal "Operational Duty Hours" - Definition. (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Carrier's Exhibit 99. Civil Air Regulations "Airman Rules" (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Carrier's Exhibit 100. Flight Assignments (Domestic) as would be under Flight Engineer International Association proposal (Box 1, Folder 101)
- Carrier's Exhibit 101. Flight Assignments (International) as would be under Flight Engineers International Association proposal (Box 1, Folder 102)
- Carrier's Exhibit 102. International Flight Crew Assignments under Flight Engineer International Association proposal (Box 1, Folder 103)
- Carrier's Exhibit 103. International Flight Engineer Assignments under Flight Engineers International Association proposal, piston. (Box 1, Folder 104)
- Carrier's Exhibit 104. Cost Estimates - Flight Engineers International Association proposal (Box 1, Folder 105)
- Carrier's Exhibit 105. Summary - Monthly hours pay and credit (turbine and piston) (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Carrier's Exhibit 106. International Flight Crew Assignments (1 for 3.5 hours) (Box 1, Folder 107)
- Carrier's Exhibit 107. International Flight Engineer flight hours and requirements (piston) (1 for 3.5) (Box 1, Folder 108)
- Carrier's Exhibit 108. Comparison of Increased Expense at proposed rates (Box 1, Folder 109)
- Carrier's Exhibit 109. Company Proposal - Section IV - Training Pay. (Box 1, Folder 110)
- Carrier's Exhibit 110. Company Proposal - Section V - Deadhead Time. (Box 1, Folder 111)
- Carrier's Exhibit 111. Company Proposal - Section X - Vacations. (Box 1, Folder 112)
- Carrier's Exhibit 112. Vacation Allowance (Comparison between 11 airlines). (Box 1, Folder 113)
- Carrier's Exhibit 113. Company Proposal - Section XI - Salary Continuance for Sickness (B). (Box 1, Folder 114)
- Carrier's Exhibit 114. Company Proposal - Section XI - Salary Continuance for Sickness (C). (Box 1, Folder 115)
- Carrier's Exhibit 115. Company Proposal - Section XI - Salary Continuance for Sickness (F) (Box 1, Folder 116)
- Carrier's Exhibit 116. Company Proposal - Section XII - Leave of Absence. (Box 1, Folder 117)
- Carrier's Exhibit 117. Company Proposal - Section XVII - Reductions, Displacement, Furlough, and return from other duty. (Box 1, Folder 118)
- Carrier's Exhibit 118. Management Policy and Procedure Manual - Insurance. (Box 1, Folder 119)
- Carrier's Exhibit 119. Company Proposal - Section VIII - Expenses (C). (Box 1, Folder 120)
- Carrier's Exhibit 120. Flight Engineer Rates for Hotel-Motel (Domestic). (Box 1, Folder 121)
- Carrier's Exhibit 121. Percent Wage Increase, Pilots and Flight Engineers., 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 122)
- Carrier's Exhibit 122. Interim Agreement (Bulletin)., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  October 14, 1960
- Association Exhibit 1. Union contract proposals (Box 1, Folder 124)
- Association Exhibit 2. Supplemental statement on report of Feinsinger Commission., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 125)
- Association Exhibit 3. National Airlines letter to President regarding Feinsinger Commission report. (Box 1, Folder 126)
  November 2, 1961.
- Association Exhibit 4. Pamphlet, "Safety in the Jet Age." (Box 1, Folder 127)
- Association Exhibit 5. Leaflet, "Convair Traveler." (Box 1, Folder 128)
- Association Exhibit 6. Flight Engineers by status., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  February 1, 1962
- Association Exhibit 7. Flight Engineer seniority list., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  January 1, 1962.
- Association Exhibit 8. Flight Engineer seniority list., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  January 1, 1958.
- Association Exhibit 9. Number and age of Flight Engineers., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  July 1, 1961
- Association Exhibit 10. Types of Trans World Airlines aircraft., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  March 28, 1962.
- Association Exhibit 11. Civil Air Regulations, Part 35. (Box 1, Folder 134)
- Association Exhibit 12. Civil Air Regulations, Part 40. (Box 1, Folder 135)
- Association Exhibit 13. Civil Air Regulations, Part 41. (Box 1, Folder 136)
- Association Exhibit 14. Cost of Living Index. (Box 1, Folder 137)
- Association Exhibit 15. Productivity factor, total private economy. (Box 1, Folder 138)
- Association Exhibit 16. Comparison of selected ratios, piston versus jet operations. (Box 1, Folder 139)
- Association Exhibit 17. National Airlines - Flight Engineers International Association Agreement; Engineers' pay scale., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 140)
  August 24, 1961.
- Association Exhibit 18. Federal Aviation Administration Announcement for "Flight Engineer Specialist." (Box 1, Folder 141)
- Association Exhibit 19. Union's requested schedule of salary continuance by years of service. (Box 1, Folder 142)
- Association Exhibit 20. Trans World Airlines Group Insurance Bulletin. (Box 1, Folder 143)
- Association Exhibit 21. Trans World Airlines Group Insurance pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 144)
- Association Exhibit 22. Example of Flight Engineer pay, trip and duty rig. (Box 1, Folder 145)
- Association Exhibit 23. Qualifications - Flight Engineers. (Box 1, Folder 146)
- Association Exhibit 24. Wall Street Journal - Cooke on Trans World Airlines Troubles. (Box 1, Folder 147)
  March 26, 1962.
- Association Exhibit 25. Excerpt Eastern Air Lines Emergency Board Number 144, Transcript. (Box 1, Folder 148)
- Association Exhibit 26. Intercarrier comparison of Flight Engineer pay. (Box 1, Folder 149)
- Association Exhibit 27. National Air Line rates, DC-8, DC-7, DC-6. (Box 1, Folder 150)
- Association Exhibit 28. Comparison piston and jet Flight Engineer wages round trip, Rome. (Box 1, Folder 151)
- Association Exhibit 29. Comparison piston and jet Flight Engineer wages round trip, Frankfurt. (Box 1, Folder 152)
- Association Exhibit 30. Comparison piston and jet Flight Engineer wages round trip, Paris. (Box 1, Folder 153)
- Association Exhibit 31. Comparison Flight Engineer wages (International., 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 154)
  1959 and 1961.
- Association Exhibit 32. Comparison Flight Engineer wages(International), 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 155)
  1959 and 1962.
- Association Exhibit 33. Flight Engineers' hourly and per mile pay. (Box 1, Folder 156)
- Association Exhibit 34. Trans World Airlines Policy on third crew for jet. (Box 1, Folder 157)
- Association Exhibit 35. Trunk line 1961 On-Time performance. (Box 1, Folder 158)
- Association Exhibit 36. Costs converting 4- to 3-man crew, Boeing 707-131. (Box 1, Folder 159)
- Joint Exhibit 1. Agreement., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 160)
  July 29, 1958.
- Joint Exhibit 2. Union's reopening notice., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 161)
  October 26, 1960.
- Joint Exhibit 3. Company's reply., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 162)
  October 27, 1960.
- Joint Exhibit 4. Union reply., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 163)
  October 31, 1960.
- Joint Exhibit 5. No information available. (Box 1, Folder 164)
- Joint Exhibit 6. Union's request for mediation. (Box 1, Folder 165)
- Joint Exhibit 7. Company's request for mediation., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 166)
  December 29, 1960.
- Joint Exhibit 8. Company telegram to Mediation Board regarding issues., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 167)
  March 17, 1961.
- Joint Exhibit National Mediation Board telegram to Company regarding issues., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 168)
  March 20, 1961.
- Joint Exhibit 10. National Mediation Board proffers arbitration., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 169)
  July 19, 1961.
- Joint Exhibit 11. National Mediation Board letter to parties noting Union rejection of arbitration, and terminating services., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 170)
  August 16, 1962.
- Joint Exhibit 12. National Mediation Board letter closing file., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 171)
  September 15, 1961.
- Joint Exhibit 13. Union strike notice., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 172)
  March 18, 1962.
- Joint Exhibit 14. Company News gram regarding strike notice., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 173)
  March 19, 1962.
- Joint Exhibit 15. National Mediation Board telegram regarding Emergency Board., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 174)
  March 20, 1962.
- Joint Exhibit 16. Union withdrawal of strike notice., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 175)
- Joint Exhibit 17. Agreement, Pan American and Flight Engineers International Association., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 176)
  November 1, 1957.
- Joint Exhibit 18. Agreement, American Airlines and Flight Engineers International Association., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 177)
  May 1, 1958.
- Joint Exhibit 19. Agreement, National Airlines and Flight Engineers International Association. (Box 1, Folder 178)
- Joint Exhibit 20. Agreement, Eastern Airlines and Flight Engineers International Association. (Box 1, Folder 179)
- Joint Exhibit 21. Kelliher Award. (Box 1, Folder 180)
- Joint Exhibit 22. Decision of Judge Duncan (Air Line Pilots Association versus Trans World Airlines)., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 181)
- Joint Exhibit 23. Agreement, Trans World Airlines and Air Line Pilots Association, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 182)
  May 22, 1959